Speaker 1: It's Thursday, May 2nd, 2024.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott And this is the geek nights book club tonight.
Speaker 1: The night is short.
Speaker 1: walk on girl by Tomohiko Morimi.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's the geek guys book club.
Speaker 1: We're actually doing these at a reasonable pace.
Speaker 0: when we don't pick a book that's a thousand pages long We don't tell we don't climb the tower.
Speaker 1: That is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: Well when there's when we don't pick one book that's actually like seven to fourteen books.
Speaker 0: yeah mind into one book.
Speaker 1: But also, you know, we're traveled a lot.
Speaker 0: It's interesting real of time.
Speaker 0: Imagine if we did no, no, no, the book club book is the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I mean, I read the whole thing pretty quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did not.
Speaker 0: I stopped at a reasonable point.
Speaker 1: There's a number of things we could unpack about the fact that I've read the entire wheel of time Kind of faster.
Speaker 0: The only one thing we need to unpack is that any time we read any kind of series rim will then proceed to read the Entire series.
Speaker 1: it just happens without I want to or not.
Speaker 0: I should find a series.
Speaker 0: I should.
Speaker 0: I should just do like Hardy Boys the first ever I Read or Nancy.
Speaker 1: I might have read almost all of the Hardy Boys books.
Speaker 1: I was really into those as a kid.
Speaker 0: I also read are like a hundred.
Speaker 0: are there hundreds of them.
Speaker 1: I read a lot of Hardy Boys.
Speaker 0: All right, we'll do like babysitter's club, it's probably like a thousand of them.
Speaker 1: I only read a couple of those.
Speaker 1: I didn't read all the boxcar children either.
Speaker 0: or what's that one that they sell at the in the romance section at the You know the drugstore that's always like letters of the alphabet like a is for this and B is for whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if I know what you're talking about or if I just my brain made up a memory of seeing those.
Speaker 0: What is the longest by number of books book series?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Hardy Boys.
Speaker 0: There is what they're saying like a hundred and ninety.
Speaker 0: So I doubt I read all the different.
Speaker 0: if you had all the different series together.
Speaker 0: It's like 400.
Speaker 0: So when
Speaker 1: I was a kid, well one of our bookshelves, I wonder might have an old picture of it We had like an entire shelf just dedicated to the Hardy Boys and another shelf that had The like later newer Hardy Boys books which were kind of edge lordy and stupid.
Speaker 1: But what do you want?
Speaker 1: I was like 11.
Speaker 0: They're also 41 Discworld books.
Speaker 0: you could we could do that.
Speaker 1: I can only think of one novel I ever Started reading.
Speaker 1: it was a series of three novels But they were condensed into one giant hardcover and it's the only book of real length I ever started reading Made it significantly into and then just decided to not continue and give up on and never read And that was dragons gold serpent silver chimeras copper.
Speaker 0: I don't know how those books end nor do I know how you can say I don't know how you can say the name of it without tongue-twisting Remembering which things what the title even is Out of that.
Speaker 1: this is how much I despised those books Kind of like how the worst movie I've ever watched to completion on purpose remains Clifford with Martin Short playing a ten-year-old boy.
Speaker 1: Okay So the night is short walk on girl.
Speaker 1: that were again.
Speaker 1: if you're new to the geek nights book club somehow We've read the book and it's a book club.
Speaker 1: that means we're assuming you dear listener have read the book.
Speaker 1: So if you have not read the book the night is short walk on girl.
Speaker 1: or at least Watch the movie that we also reviewed that is also titled that I just short walk on girl Then you're not gonna know what we're talking about and we're gonna ruin everything about this book like spoilers.
Speaker 1: Just read the book.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna summarize the entire plot for you.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be a conversation about among people who have read this book.
Speaker 0: Hmm Yeah, so the first the first thing you got to know is about this author, right?
Speaker 1: So I don't know too much about them But I know I know is every piece of media they have been involved in that I have encountered so far I have loved and as a result, I feel like I should read all of their books.
Speaker 1: There aren't even that many, right?
Speaker 0: so basically it's like we saw, you know various anime from science saurus such as tatami galaxy Highway Right and the tatami time machine blues, which is newer family Right.
Speaker 0: Well eccentric family is not from science.
Speaker 1: Sorry, but it's a show.
Speaker 1: it is.
Speaker 0: It is still an anime that is based on the novels of this person.
Speaker 0: so it's like wow this person keeps having their novels adapted into anime quite a bit and all of those anime are like Fantastic for some reason.
Speaker 0: so clearly the novels must be good And that was why I gave rim a choice between like hey a novel by this person the novel the new Miyazaki movie was based on.
Speaker 1: It was hard to pass this one up, especially because the night is a walk-on girl.
Speaker 1: The night is short.
Speaker 1: I always say it the opposite way like I can't a randomly say but it's the night is short walk-on girl.
Speaker 1: That movie really stuck with me.
Speaker 1: Like that was a fantastic film.
Speaker 1: I'd like to say about it.
Speaker 1: We reviewed it.
Speaker 1: we did a pretty long review of it some years ago on geek nights and If I had to summarize what struck me about that movie other than its visual style it was that Despite being written effect essentially about Japanese college students It felt so true to the spirit of my experience as an American college student in very particular ways and It just there was.
Speaker 1: it like it just really spoke to me in my life and how I've lived up to this point.
Speaker 1: And people I have known like I watched that movie and I read this book and there's a lot of people in these books Or in this book that I can think.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like this person.
Speaker 1: I knew that's like katsu That's like whatever.
Speaker 1: like there's these characters that just they're the larger-than-life archetypes of the underwear guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah hundred percent thousand percent.
Speaker 0: But yes, I mean Tomohiko Marimi is only a few years older than us right and basically they went to college.
Speaker 0: They went to Kyoto University and a lot of the books They write are either take our set in Kyoto or and this one Kyoto and Kyoto University.
Speaker 0: so it's like they're explicitly writing about their own college days in a fantastical kind of way You know.
Speaker 0: and so if you have sort of a similar University Experience then that's gonna speak to you because they're speaking about the same thing that they had.
Speaker 1: Then it really did speak to me.
Speaker 1: I mean like just reading this book really brought it back.
Speaker 1: But the one big difference then we'll stop talking about the movie because we're all authors.
Speaker 1: God is dead.
Speaker 1: Other works are dead.
Speaker 1: we're only talking about the book.
Speaker 1: but a Big difference is the movie portrays everything that happens in this book as basically occurring in one crazy night All the way through to the end and then there's entirely.
Speaker 1: well then there's the denim on like the final sickness story in the winter.
Speaker 0: But this book I mean Yeah, the movie it sort of feels like it's one crazy night because they don't do a great job of like letting you know Like, you know the whole season later, right?
Speaker 0: It just sort of keeps going right very quickly without like any sort of indication other right Until the sickness part.
Speaker 1: where then it does have like a pause in the beat?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like were there four seasons in one night.
Speaker 0: or is it just not really breaking between?
Speaker 0: whereas in the book You have four chapters one for each season four seasons in a row covering the entire school year Ending, you know starting in the spring and ending in the winter.
Speaker 0: Alright, one two, three four.
Speaker 0: and this it's it's a. it's like chapter one over chapter two next season And it breaks it up into four distinct parts right the night of drunkenness the.
Speaker 0: The second one is the book fair the book fair and then the school festival and then everyone and then the plague.
Speaker 1: once you have spring summer fall winter, which I think is important.
Speaker 1: because what reading the book?
Speaker 1: one thing that really struck me is that it very much feels like these are the four seasons of Coming into adulthood while you're in college from the naive.
Speaker 1: I have come to school.
Speaker 1: The world is my oyster.
Speaker 1: I can do anything.
Speaker 1: I'm an invincible God.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go have a night on the town to the summer To the fall the melancholy.
Speaker 1: remember that feeling of leaving like leaving campus.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: I think it's also that you know.
Speaker 0: just in Japan They common sense have school start when the year starts in school and when the year ends not like Whatever we do in the United States for who knows what reason.
Speaker 0: where school starts in the autumn It's like it doesn't even make sense.
Speaker 0: You try to be like well back in the day They were very agrarian.
Speaker 0: And so the kids had to work the harvest.
Speaker 0: Well, then why are they starting school at the same time as the harvest?
Speaker 0: That's not the reason that we do.
Speaker 0: I don't know the reason we do it that way in the United States.
Speaker 0: I actually don't know stupid and they we should change it.
Speaker 0: I think they should just delay the start of a school year at some point like three months just to line it up January, you know, there's a lot of things we could do to make our schools better.
Speaker 1: But I guess the seasons really matter here because it like winter the final chapter Really feels like that peak or that trough about nadir of your life as a college student.
Speaker 1: that moment when?
Speaker 1: You're becoming an adult for real.
Speaker 1: because you know, we were old we were above the age of 18 in college.
Speaker 1: But at the same time we're all stupid like that's just how you are when you're between 18 and 20 something.
Speaker 1: and this book just really parallels and highlights some of the ways that people Evolve in college and that particular kind of adolescence if they get to experience it.
Speaker 0: All right, so in the book you got the two characters you got the dude and the girl who's walking on yep, and The book is told in first-person perspective from both of them and it switches back and forth.
Speaker 0: so it's like, you know, we've seen books like say Prince of Nothing where it's like Ah, this chapter is looking over here these characters Chapters looking over at those characters and you saw there's a lot of books doing that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But this one is like first person character a first person character B And these characters don't really directly interact a lot until the and they do at some points But very slightly and then at the end Right because it's a. it's a typical romance thing where the people aren't together and then at the end, haha, they're together.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah But they're interacting a lot with the same other people, right.
Speaker 0: So it's like they interact with the rich drunken guy with the train.
Speaker 0: they interact with the bedroom investigation society.
Speaker 0: They interact with the the club fair festival leading guy and The you know underpants guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: but most importantly there's two kids.
Speaker 1: the two characters They react with the most are almost a good use of them.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Higuchi and mr.
Speaker 0: Wada Hanuki Drunk lady on the keys and the guys yet and the guy who's probably a Tengu the Tengu guy who's in all the anime And it's like they're constantly interacting with the same people but not each other.
Speaker 0: And so what happens is I don't know if this is it happens in the Japanese.
Speaker 0: Obviously that goes for basically everything.
Speaker 0: because we read a translated book But the you start reading a section because it's not broken.
Speaker 0: It's like the four chapters are for the four seasons.
Speaker 0: So they'll be like a dot in.
Speaker 0: you'll be reading and then there'll be a dot.
Speaker 0: and it's like the dot means next part Right of the same chapter that we haven't changed seasons yet and it just sort of starts going in.
Speaker 0: when the first person like I was hanging out with the at the Speedy kotatsu, whatever right or you know, I went into the next bar and Higuchi was there and it's like is this Character a or character B?
Speaker 0: Alright and sometimes it's perfectly clear which one it is because you can get a hint of like.
Speaker 0: yeah We I know the other character is currently in this situation.
Speaker 0: yeah, this can't be them.
Speaker 0: that the dude right now is in like a Eating contest of eating like the fire Whatever it was, right?
Speaker 0: And so this isn't about eating fire curry and that's not resolved yet.
Speaker 0: So this is clearly the girl talking right now but sometimes it's not entirely clear and nothing in that section.
Speaker 0: like definitively Like, you know and most of the time it does.
Speaker 0: but there are a few times Where it's not a hundred.
Speaker 0: you could you could bet on one over the other But it's not a hundred percent guaranteed.
Speaker 1: that that was the character Yeah It might be the translation of it and that the tone felt the same Whenever.
Speaker 0: I think they just come in like start narrating like I walked into the woods like who were you?
Speaker 1: Right, I'm glad that wasn't just me because I at least ten times reading this book would be steamrolling through and then I'd have to Backup a couple of variables like wait.
Speaker 1: Wait, that's the girl.
Speaker 1: That's the girl.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it's not.
Speaker 0: they don't do right these strict Alternating.
Speaker 0: it doesn't go a hundred percent back and forth back and forth.
Speaker 0: There are times I checked where it's like same character dot same character still All right, just doing stepped on to the next part of the story or whatever.
Speaker 0: So you can't just rely on some alternation like in.
Speaker 0: you know, what was the the loved one?
Speaker 0: We did the book with the How to had it.
Speaker 0: the time war right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah how to lose the time war?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're all.
Speaker 0: so I couldn't kill the characters apart, but that one was strictly alternating.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm right here.
Speaker 1: They're not strictly altered But in this case the while the tone Was the same in terms of how it was written again with the caveat that the translation might have colored that to some degree.
Speaker 1: The the outlook and the way the characters perceive the same events and interact with the world Couldn't be more different.
Speaker 1: Like you're really Don't super like the guy and the girl is just like charming and cute all the time With almost no exceptions, like the guy's not bad He's not evil, but he is.
Speaker 1: I would describe him as stupid in the way that a lot of guys in college Tend to be.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think that's the thing about the guy is like he is You know, he's not like a just a bad dude Like I got evil bro or a sleazy person Nora, right or that guy Right, but he is since you're getting his inns inner monologue Right.
Speaker 0: He's sort of exposing to you the reader all his dark inner thoughts, which you know are Kind of realistic for her somewhat a dude that age, right?
Speaker 0: And or at least, you know, I had those kinds of thoughts at times in my life, right.
Speaker 0: And there's like this like he's like having like these introspective like arguments with himself Like, you know at some points later in the book where he's like do I even like this girl?
Speaker 0: It's like I just am I just a pervert, you know, he's like.
Speaker 0: well, you know, I do have those thoughts But also these other things right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, but doesn't everybody?
Speaker 0: or it's like.
Speaker 0: is that okay?
Speaker 0: Is it not?
Speaker 0: Okay what you know?
Speaker 0: He's not just like, you know, an actual evil person would have been like, you know, like not thinking those things.
Speaker 0: And so it's like that sort of makes it more sympathetic than in the movie where you know You see the way like his is in the movie.
Speaker 0: It's like his body language and his personality and it's sort of like hey get this guy out of here.
Speaker 1: But especially because without all that introspection the movie really just the girl is so great He's like, why is she ended up with this this pots?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: The book really makes it more clear that they did actually have a lot in common And there is a lot more going on in the broader world of how they're connected to each other, etc.
Speaker 1: But that really just didn't come through in the movie the movie.
Speaker 1: I just didn't want that guy to be her out.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the movie.
Speaker 0: They definitely seemed more like somebody Stalking slash having a crush on someone from afar Whereas in the book it's like, you know clearly is like they're in this club together.
Speaker 0: They don't name what club that is.
Speaker 0: They talk about every other club, right, but they are in a club together.
Speaker 0: It's like they you know, they meet all that, you know frequently but that's partly intentional due to stalking But somehow it he does a non creepy stalking which they use the metaphor of like filling in the moat Right.
Speaker 0: It's like because on the one hand he's too cowardly to just ask a girl out which but As a guy who was in college, we've all been there.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah That's normal, right?
Speaker 0: You know, so he's too cowardly to ask a girl out which is relatable but at the same time he is Conscientious enough to not want to like, you know harass and and you know barge through the the front door of the castle Right and be a bad dude, right?
Speaker 0: He wants to make sure that there is some sort of at least some Confirmation of a reciprocal feeling before he does anything right?
Speaker 0: So the metaphor uses that he's filling in the moat, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I don't have to go, you know Swimming across the water and attack like a barbarian.
Speaker 1: if the moat is filled in then I could walk into the castle casually, but he's also really approaching it in that naive way as an outsider instead of just like making a human connection and Talking to this person.
Speaker 0: Well, I think is that you know it.
Speaker 0: the the argument at least that's made towards the end of the book is that yeah He did have the this sort of weird approach that was somewhat stalker and uncomfortable due to his cowardice and whatnot, but also somehow his his moat filling did create some moments of Connection right?
Speaker 0: They were just very brief, but they still were remembered by both people later, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's like oh, I'm actually gonna go on a date with this person now actually, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, what will we talk about?
Speaker 0: Well, I really you know, they're both curious about how the other person's night went and when they were all drunk, you know.
Speaker 0: They're both curious about What happened with at the book fair right where.
Speaker 0: and then they're right.
Speaker 0: so they have.
Speaker 0: they do have those things that he did.
Speaker 0: You know, he was thinking about her.
Speaker 0: he went and ate the hottest curry to get the book.
Speaker 1: They didn't remember like a selfless acts didn't remember like completely in a vacuum.
Speaker 1: part of that memory was being prompted by the fact that these two had interacted with all these other people.
Speaker 1: and then the cold at the end really brings together like oh everyone is connected in this college like this is an environment that people live in and People don't exist in a vacuum.
Speaker 1: They're they're coming together.
Speaker 1: and these coincidences were partly through the network of all the other people they know.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you think about in the real world I feel like the people I know who have relationships.
Speaker 0: a lot of the best relationships were people who had that level of connection with each other prior right where it's like.
Speaker 0: You know, I think about people who are like best friends like super close since they were young.
Speaker 0: It's like I've.
Speaker 0: that can work out right.
Speaker 0: but you know, yeah, it's a little weird You see this but it's like Yeah, a complete distant stranger right that you.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah, but it's like oh, you know We you know, I'm friends with so-and-so you're friends with your so-and-so's cousin Right, and then we meet at a wedding right as there was a wedding meeting at the start of this book.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the like the most common kind of distance that people have where there is a common Thing for them to discuss and they do share, you know some part of the world with each other not complete strangers But they're not super close.
Speaker 0: They already know everything about each other.
Speaker 0: that would make a relationship awkward and these two characters are portrayed as having that exact amount of connection Even though you may not realize it until you know later on.
Speaker 1: So one thing that really struck me was that the of all the side characters which are great Like I can I've never read a book.
Speaker 1: That's so well Portrayed what it feels like to be in a college and have like the cast of weirdos that are in the periphery of your social Circles like.
Speaker 1: it reminded me a lot of how we felt and acted around like RIT anime and our wag and like oh That's the weird guy where there's a mythology around him.
Speaker 1: Like everyone has a mythology But the book bit by bit as you get even a little bit closer to any of these mythological Characters the more real they become.
Speaker 1: like you see the reality like Like Rihaku is this old man and you get a much more balanced portrayal of him.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Ms.
Speaker 1: Hanuki like she's this legendary semi magical drunk but now she works in a dentist office and she's just an older woman and like you kind of mythologized her because you'd never really interacted with adults before college kid not on that level.
Speaker 1: and And Similarly to think about RIT the mythology of running RIT anime.
Speaker 1: But the reality was we're a bunch of nerds read a club for a little while.
Speaker 1: That was that like there wasn't anything special.
Speaker 1: There's another.
Speaker 1: there's someone there who's probably similar to how I was and similar to how you were and they got their katsu Just like we had our katsu.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a. I highlighted something but I didn't.
Speaker 0: of course I left my ebook in the other room same.
Speaker 1: I highlighted a few lines that I'll have to try to remember because I don't have it open.
Speaker 0: let me see if I can get it in the Cloud version but I guess of the.
Speaker 1: while you pull that up the character what?
Speaker 1: what struck me the most is that mr Higuchi the Tengu guy Was very much pair up parallel of the main character.
Speaker 1: the guy in the same way that miss Hanuki was very much a parallel of The girl main character.
Speaker 1: and in the first chapter, they really felt almost like on one hand Through the adolescent eyes interacting with an adult like oh, how cool is this guy?
Speaker 1: Like to have it like having this crazy night doing cool stuff in the bars.
Speaker 1: But you get a little older and you realize like oh that guy's just kind of poor and shabby and he's a cool guy But it's not magic.
Speaker 1: and meanwhile like Oh miss Hanuki.
Speaker 1: She's so elegant with her cocktail now She's just kind of a middle-aged drunk.
Speaker 1: Like don't don't Think that she's more than that, but the characters also almost Saw them through the lens of how they idealize themselves as adults in some ways because the guy definitely like was very much into philosophy and very much into like solving problems different ways like you could see him almost imagining in the hotpot contest like I wish I were a Tengu and I could Use magic to win it instead of this bullshit of having to eat this bad food and the girl drinking her cocktails is seeing her As wow, I wish I could be that elegant sneaking into a party.
Speaker 1: Everyone loves me.
Speaker 1: I know my way through the world like this and they're almost like following in the footsteps of these adults, but they're following their Mythological idealized version of these adults they met.
Speaker 0: Yeah so the part that I the thing that I highlighted right was talking about the school festival and it's like and it says What were they trying to impart to people at the booths in the lecture halls and on the stage?
Speaker 0: They displayed an excess of free time and feudal enthusiasm And there was nothing whatsoever interesting about that to outsiders.
Speaker 0: in other words It was none other than despicable raw youth Right, and so that's what's on display in this book, right?
Speaker 0: Is that that sort of youth where it's not the youth of children, right?
Speaker 0: But it's the youth of not an adult yet?
Speaker 0: Yeah And so, you know you think about you know things that you do in your life around that time For some reason for I guess I don't know of all people but at least for us and Tomohiko Morimi Anyone
Speaker 1: who was lucky wealthy whatever enough to go to a proper college
Speaker 0: and might happen outside of colleges, too.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but there's a different flavor of it.
Speaker 1: But this is very so specifically highlighting that University style of yes hairless youth.
Speaker 0: but it's not just the people Around that time in your life that can sort of have a mythological right kind of you know, aura but also the events Right.
Speaker 0: It's like that time we played battle tech down in the base.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we played battle tech in a basement.
Speaker 0: There was nothing.
Speaker 1: Music night was like this legendary night that would happen a couple times a year.
Speaker 1: but if you took a photograph of an anime music night or Showed someone who was not inside that environment what music I was actually like They would not see a mythology.
Speaker 1: They would see a bunch of nerds in a room listening to anime music.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's just you know, you.
Speaker 0: it's for some reason people will be like, oh remember, you know, even when they are adults They'll say remember that time this thing happened that crazy drunken night in you know around town.
Speaker 0: Remember that crate remember that book fair remember that school festival with the elephant, but it's like and you get that those are those are the times.
Speaker 0: and then you look but you don't have.
Speaker 0: you can't think of any of those times in your Recent life.
Speaker 0: Oh No, because you're looking at even though you might be doing things that are that level or even beyond that level They don't take on that sort of aura.
Speaker 0: It's just like ah that time, you know that time we went to Fancy restaurant.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, what's a fancy restaurant?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're like I'd like I Me bumming around Turkey for months As a job getting into weird situations that I was very mythological.
Speaker 1: but yet it looms equally large in my personal memory to like That one particular club night where like the most people showed up and I almost won the DDR tournament Almost I didn't actually win.
Speaker 1: but also like the structures the school itself like the fact that like the clock tower is there and he acknowledges it a lot and Mentions it a lot and talks to it when he's walking by Felt a lot like me looking at that one sculpture on campus every day like walking over to go to class or whatever.
Speaker 1: Like there's just something magical about that kind of environment and I don't think it's just youth.
Speaker 1: I think it's that it's the last.
Speaker 1: it's the time in the life of someone who has that experience where you have the most possibilities in front of you, but you are also Adult enough to be taking real actions independently.
Speaker 1: You're living independently.
Speaker 1: You're you're your own.
Speaker 1: You're the master of your own domain.
Speaker 1: your decisions are your own but you also haven't been crushed by the world yet.
Speaker 1: You don't have any real responsibilities yet.
Speaker 1: And everything you do is like your currency is idle time.
Speaker 0: I Think it's also that in that kind of space the the way people are defined, right?
Speaker 0: So I think about this a lot or it's like you look at a person.
Speaker 0: it's like Joey Jojo and it's like All right, if you have to write a one-sentence bio for Joey Jojo's social media profile, right?
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of people will put their job.
Speaker 0: a lot of people will put.
Speaker 0: if the people have created something, right?
Speaker 0: They're a founder.
Speaker 0: They're an artist, right?
Speaker 0: They'll put the thing that they made.
Speaker 0: if the person is like has really not done much They're gonna put the thing that they like consume like I'm a Star Wars.
Speaker 0: Right the things that they enjoy will define who they are as people, right?
Speaker 0: I play this video game that defines me, right?
Speaker 0: And so once you're like, you know an adult out of college You know, you sort of are gonna have probably a job or a thing.
Speaker 0: You've made.
Speaker 0: that is the thing that defines you right, but before then right what defines you?
Speaker 0: is Not any of that right?
Speaker 0: it's like, you know, there's a hundred people in the same, you know engineering major.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like right.
Speaker 0: You're not defining people by God.
Speaker 0: so and so the engineering major.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know anyone in my major except katsu.
Speaker 0: and like right is you're saying ah That weird that weird guy who always wears the Viking hat.
Speaker 0: or it's like that guy who you know Is always.
Speaker 1: you know, there's the fancy camera guy Like I was if you're anyone wrote that one sentence about me at RIT.
Speaker 1: That's that weird guy with the mustache who runs our ITL who runs the anime club, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's all people have you know some sort of other weird Quirky almost, you know thing that defines them.
Speaker 0: That is the kind of thing that you would only see for like characters in a novel or a movie and you don't really see Too much among, you know If you go to work you think about your co-workers, I don't think about any of those people in that way, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, I have a co-worker who wears like.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think of my co-workers.
Speaker 0: There's one who has like, you know, they're their glasses are like a somewhat outlandish style, right?
Speaker 0: Not a typical normal style eyeglasses that you know, they got some wild frames wilder than normal, right?
Speaker 0: And but do I think about them as person with the wild glasses?
Speaker 1: Not really they aren't like the legendary but that guy hasn't changed his underwear in seven months.
Speaker 1: you remember that right?
Speaker 0: It's like underwear guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hey, or you know, you got any.
Speaker 0: you need to go to conventions.
Speaker 0: We see a little bit of that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I don't know banana maraca.
Speaker 0: It's like there's a guy like who's like a sort of taken on an aura being banana maraca.
Speaker 1: or you know line management hat feather guy, I think part of it cuz packs like conventions are Micro spaces brief moments in space and time that are very similar to that youthful excess of Individual identity that we get in like in college like we're here at a magfest.
Speaker 1: people who wouldn't otherwise be remarkable in broader society are wearing a weird costume or are the spotted guy who wanders around playing spotted with people or like It.
Speaker 1: lets you relive that and if you never lived it Then I think that's why I can mention might be a very important space for you because that's where you can be What you want to be in a in the sense that these identities are not just how you see yourself Nor are they just how other people see you.
Speaker 1: something about these.
Speaker 1: the way these mythological identities are portrayed in this book feels very real To college.
Speaker 1: it's sort of mutual and consensual like people would know.
Speaker 1: Oh rim That's the weird guy with the mustache who runs RIT anime.
Speaker 1: But I thought of myself as I'm gonna be the fucking weird guy who runs RIT anime like I wanted that identity I reveled in that identity.
Speaker 1: underpants guy in the book reveled in that identity.
Speaker 0: Well, I also think you know when we look at the internet, you know the social media.
Speaker 0: It's like the older internet had more of that going on.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you made it.
Speaker 0: when you made geocities page you were that flaming skull guy or chowder man, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas on the social medias we have today you are you.
Speaker 0: you are who you are and it's only in certain you know still cool online spaces like maybe a VR chat kind of place.
Speaker 0: or you know neo cities or you know strange discords or people with Video Vtubers right where you know, you're.
Speaker 0: you're some kind of caricature or character But that care even though it's a character or a front.
Speaker 0: It might actually be more true to who you are because
Speaker 1: I think uninhibited trueness of self and society In a man much of the world But especially in the United States and Japan in the modern era does not give you a lot of safety freedom or space To live.
Speaker 1: that identity like I can't be the way I was at RIT anime at work Even though I am very much still like that in real life in person most of the time But not.
Speaker 1: but I said real life as opposed to work.
Speaker 1: very few people have a lot of time In their lives post college where they can be that way for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: And I think like.
Speaker 1: I think you and I have made a point of trying to keep that as strong as possible.
Speaker 1: but even then like a lot of my social media is very mercenary like Even we get battered down by society.
Speaker 1: We're not.
Speaker 1: we can't be the full fully realized weirdos that we were in college that we probably would be if there was more slack In our society.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but when you think about you know, the media that we consume particularly the anime and the mangas Right a lot of them create, you know fantasy novels also Sci-fi novels.
Speaker 0: they create these worlds inhabited by people like that even in this novel, right?
Speaker 0: They're The koi fishing pond.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and it's like Rudy.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know, I imagine him as Rudy.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's like they're sort of like these special people who have like a certain You know light on them in a unique and fun character kind of way and not just a person.
Speaker 1: That is uninteresting Right, and the thing is one.
Speaker 1: one thing I think is very important is some people misinterpret this as I think in college You'll see the people of the light shining on them and you kind of assume that all the people who don't stand out are just Boring, but I think what's something this book portrays really well Is that the reality is at the cold scene at the end like the cold the sequence of who got the cold from whom?
Speaker 1: There's all these different networks in a place like a college where to someone else There's a different set of people who have the light shining on them and the groups of people who intersect will build their own Mythologies, but they're not all the same.
Speaker 1: like everyone's got that story unless they're really sad in college.
Speaker 1: God you know my life is great now like I'm not gonna complain about it, but There's a reason why so many people say all college was the best days of my life I think except for the whole studying part notice.
Speaker 0: They don't do any of this to school studying But you didn't study much.
Speaker 1: I didn't know I didn't study we didn't go to class.
Speaker 0: If you think about the amount of time spent you know going to classes and all those things.
Speaker 0: right it was the least memorable part But it was significant number of the hours.
Speaker 1: yeah More or less so for me because I I really didn't go to class like ever it depends It was it was part of my.
Speaker 1: the.
Speaker 1: the identity I had in college was everyone like.
Speaker 1: everyone knew like how is really like it Here cuz I never went to class like.
Speaker 1: it didn't seem like I was ever doing anything.
Speaker 0: But Yeah, I mean you know this is technically I guess a light novel right have we?
Speaker 0: I don't know if we've read anything else for the book club that counts as a light novel.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not really a distinction that they make so much in the United States.
Speaker 0: It's really something that came over through.
Speaker 0: you know it was a thing in Japan and then because anime fans people found out this the term sort of carried over as like this law of novels that are Quicker and easier to read but are not necessarily like.
Speaker 0: you know novellas where they're you know There's somehow lesser than right we think about.
Speaker 0: like you know we read Binti which was short, but I guess those three parts.
Speaker 1: Well, we also did way back in like 2010 2011 golden apples of the Sun which is a collection of short stories.
Speaker 0: No, that's not an anthology.
Speaker 1: That's not a light novel yeah, but we did it in the book club because I think yeah But it's not.
Speaker 0: that's not even related.
Speaker 1: I was in terms of categorizing like the book club isn't specific to novels.
Speaker 0: No, it's not not at all.
Speaker 0: It can be.
Speaker 0: we could we could do nonfiction.
Speaker 0: I just don't like.
Speaker 1: I plan to introduce a nonfiction book at some point, but I'm holding off for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: It's difficult is diff.
Speaker 0: You know it's not like.
Speaker 0: I enjoy the learning of nonfiction But it's it's hard to read.
Speaker 1: get the little as I'll point out the listener has called out that that one of the mythological Features of their college was Cutco Dave a true weirdo.
Speaker 0: there you go.
Speaker 0: That's that that's person knows exactly what the fuck we're talking about and this book is all about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Cutco Dave and dammit Duane are the same type of legend.
Speaker 0: we had dammit Had and we yeah We had a lot of people like that duck boy Lots of people, but it's just it did.
Speaker 0: this boat was Steve.
Speaker 1: this book portrayed it so well and I do feel like if their Society were more like college in that.
Speaker 1: what like?
Speaker 1: what are the attributes of the place that this book portrays?
Speaker 1: People are struggling and have work and like they still have responsibilities But the responsibilities are not as dire as a lot of people have.
Speaker 1: like you can fail and it's fine for the most part.
Speaker 1: You have a lot of free time.
Speaker 0: You he says free time and feudal enthusiasm.
Speaker 0: It says it right there in the book.
Speaker 1: I highlighted it but you're also in a very close-knit Walkable environment.
Speaker 1: you're not locked away in cars far away from each other, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I thought you know, I think in Japan in general.
Speaker 0: It's there aren't while there's still cars there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems more walkable everywhere than it, you know in the United States.
Speaker 0: but I think another thing that you can't overlook in the importance of all of Marini's work is The importance of Kyoto, right?
Speaker 0: So obviously I've never been there.
Speaker 0: I've been there Yeah, but having seen so many of it the anime and reading this book at least it's like I feel like I learned a lot of things about it.
Speaker 0: and The Marini includes so many Kyoto things as recurring themes throughout all the works.
Speaker 0: It's like the you know, the electric railway and the electric brandy and other other electric things.
Speaker 1: Well overlapping with the magical realism of Marini's works, which are a big part of this book, too.
Speaker 0: You know the the magical book fair the the guy
Speaker 1: I just love magical realist Kyoto like the right the way like if the real world had Dangerous oni guy who lives in a triple-decker train that occasionally shows up and is possibly dangerous But people get on that train anyway, because something cool will happen.
Speaker 1: I'd be on that I'd be looking for that train every night.
Speaker 0: But it's like it sort of adds that extra special something.
Speaker 0: whereas in our life We had hoagie Steve who was just a guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what if we had who knows what they're doing right now?
Speaker 0: But in if our lives are a Marini novel hoagie Steve would actually be a sandwich wizard for real kind of Questionably, like how did they eat that many sandwiches?
Speaker 0: Like how did she drink that much alcohol and not die, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it wouldn't be straight-up magic like fucking Merlin the wizard, but it would still be like no way.
Speaker 0: Anyone eats that many sandwiches.
Speaker 0: It's impossible.
Speaker 0: Right but hoagie Steve pulled it off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this would be more.
Speaker 1: it'd be more like yeah pretty sure that guy's a tanuki Like real life.
Speaker 0: Mitch drank a bunch of milk and got sick because that's what would happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the book, you know Mitch becomes a cow.
Speaker 0: I don't know Something like that, right?
Speaker 0: You hear a mysterious moo, where did that come from?
Speaker 1: But yeah, I like.
Speaker 1: I thoroughly enjoyed reading this book Even having like the movies great the books great.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to watch the movie again.
Speaker 1: Now that I've read the book
Speaker 0: I think that the thing that I also enjoy is just the in the movie this sort of like that this narration that comes in It's actually happens in a tatami galaxy Also a lot where the the character is talking and narrating from the first-person perspective like in this really rapid-fire voice, right?
Speaker 0: And so when I started reading the book I was reading it in that sort of voice and it was going way too fast.
Speaker 0: But I managed to like slow it down at least so that you know It's like the when the influence of the anime stopped infecting my my reading.
Speaker 0: But even though the speed I was able to erase and get a grip on the sort of tone And phrasing was like captured very well.
Speaker 0: so I don't know if the animes and this book had the same translators, but if Whoever did translate it they were definitely on the same page And so clearly that must be.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: The fact that all the different works have that coming through in the translation Tells me it must be in the original text as well.
Speaker 0: That's sort of that same tone of you know, this sort of Wild prose right, you know using like these ridiculous analogies for things and and you know.
Speaker 1: So one other little theme that stood out to me was that We see several occurrences.
Speaker 1: one of the clubs like having fake rivalries with each other Which again totally true to real life.
Speaker 1: RIT anime and rwag.
Speaker 1: There was nothing We actually could fight about but we kind of made up reasons to fight with each other for fun Like that's just kind of how college went.
Speaker 1: but also it portrays the adults the people who have left college.
Speaker 1: They maintain that thread back and I always think to the scene in the first chapter where the old members of the sofa Street Club Encounter.
Speaker 0: the current members of the sofa Street Club and that is often the softest are there at the end as well.
Speaker 1: Yep Imagine if you me and add like all the people who were like in that era of RIT anime Happened to be in a bar or restaurant like somewhere and we bumped into the current eboard of RIT anime Like it would be just like that.
Speaker 0: that's happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has happened.
Speaker 1: It's happened many times and every time it's happened.
Speaker 1: It has been an absolute social treasure to me but to the book definitely makes it clear that those threads are how you maintain a degree of happiness in your life like you can't like you don't want to live in the past but you want to maintain that little thread because Occasionally you can tug on that thread and be pulled back for a brief moment into what it was like in the year 2001 when you were like trying to join the eboard of a club in college.
Speaker 0: Well, it's also interesting how you know The soffit Street Club is like the first one that sort of comes in and it's sort of you know.
Speaker 0: They always talk about you know, my club mate, but they never say what club they're in.
Speaker 0: It doesn't seem to be the soffit Street Club.
Speaker 0: It's some unnamed club But the soffit Street Club is like there throughout and even not only is it there throughout the book or as the other clubs might only appear briefly, but Everyone's always engaging in soffit Street all the in the club or not.
Speaker 1: I was about I was gonna make the argument that In college at least for us every club was a soffit Street Club effect.
Speaker 0: Exactly It's like when we had the free time and feudal enthusiasm.
Speaker 0: We did a lot of soffit Street non-stop soffit Street Free time a lot less.
Speaker 0: a lot less soffit Street these days a lot more Real answers to real problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, et cetera, which you sort of get at the end of this book like the winter chapter is partly about Moving beyond that mythology into some more specific realities.
Speaker 0: Oh, it did have a magical.
Speaker 0: they have a magical cure for the disease and a magical tornado and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But So, yeah, if It's funny because I was reading through some reviews on Goodreads of this book just to see what other people have thought like interesting What was fascinating to me is they seem to break into three types of reviews that I'm gonna broadly characterize.
Speaker 1: type one is a lot like what we said like intro an introspective and Inspective analysis of the themes and morals of the book and etc.
Speaker 1: People who are just like oh, it was just like college Oh my god, this really brought me back and people who were reductive and angry about it and they seemed like there were a few reviewers of people who were like that's not what it's like like.
Speaker 1: that was just some kids like following drunk people around and having like seeing the world through stupid child eyes and they didn't get
Speaker 0: anything and
Speaker 1: other people who seemed to just react strongly to the fact that They didn't experience things like that and they couldn't relate to anything that happened in the book at all.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and I know some of our friends who didn't go to RIT with us when we watched the movie.
Speaker 1: I do remember some of them really bounced off of the movie like they didn't.
Speaker 1: they did not have an experience like that In their adolescence the way we did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think a lot of people don't especially, you know, it's it's not an experience of.
Speaker 0: You know certain kinds of people people who are might be sheltered people who might be Unfortunate people who might not, you know go to some place that has a lot of people, right?
Speaker 0: It's not an experience you have in a quieter place.
Speaker 0: You know even in a quieter place there might be characters, but there will be fewer of them, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's really Just a certain kind of experience that you know A certain kind of life has many lives, but also not many lives.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not a universal thing for all all humans.
Speaker 1: Yep but at least for our group, I'm thinking of someone a different Scott in particular the bits of the specific nature of a dude that age Pining after a girl that he won't ask out is so specific to one of our friends that was
Speaker 0: I think it's specific to a Lot of.
Speaker 1: I think it is specific to a lot of people.
Speaker 1: I think we all Experience that it's just one of our friends experienced it to the highest degree of anyone I've ever known including myself Perhaps.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I feel like I am.
Speaker 1: I just I gotta read the rest of the works by this author Especially because eccentric family is one of my favorite anime.
Speaker 1: like ever.
Speaker 0: It's a good one.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion links and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays gaming and games.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 4.0 International license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patron patrons for this geek nights What club are?
Speaker 1: Alan Joyce when Gigi drew a little tenderbread case?
Speaker 1: there makes music Chris the dog Christopher or Clinton Walton Finn Joel Hayes penny rhyme or Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin von Harl and a bunch of people whose names I will not say.
Speaker 1: Gotta pick the next book.
Speaker 1: We'll give you a little bit of break cuz it's warm out.
Speaker 1: But uh, Yeah, I gotta think about what choice I want to give Scott.
Speaker 1: So tonight after this book club, I leave you with Damn what you gonna do.
Speaker 1: What you gonna do what you gonna do what you gonna do What you gonna do What you gonna do?
Speaker 1: What what you gonna do when I'm fucking small like one inch tall You won't see me coming it up when I crawl into your ear late at night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're gonna be right motherfucker sleep tight and you think I'm just another bad dream But I'm a tiny little man in your bloodstream little hands holding an artery shut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's right motherfucker.
Speaker 1: What?